Balaji J

Data Engineer with 3 years of experience in offering dedication to deliver effective technical solutions with strong mindset of learning new technologies, exponential upgradation of Skillset, good critical thinking & problem solving skills, Also self-motivated and capable enough in analyzing huge data to capture meaningful insights to solve business problems along with ample hands-on experience of data analysis using SQL ETL operations and PowerBI dashboard building skilled with developing data pipelines using tools like Data factory and Apache Kafka.

balajigowdaj23@gmail.com

Chennai, India

github.com/Balaji-Gowda

9701660072

in linkedin.com/in/balaji-j-msc

WORK EXPERIENCE

Data Analyst

Trimble Inc.

06/2022 - Present Chennai

ViewPoint Analytics

- ERP Data transfer from SQL cloud database to Snowflake data cloud in JSON format through Kafka connectors.
- Performing ETL on raw Kafka topics using SQL in various levels and storing the data in tabular format.
- Applying data mining and transforming data to business relevant output using complex SQL queries automated with Snowflake Streams and Tasks and storing as Views.
- Projecting Views to Power BI and visualizing the Constructional data with multiple KPI's and charts built using DAX to provide insights for Users about their customers and field workers which are then deployed to final portal via PowerBI server.
- Implemented a chatbot for Analytics users to access ERP documentation content with ease that built using Python, NLP transformers and flask framework.

Programmer Analyst

Cognizant Technology Solutions

12/2020 - 06/2022 Philips Sales Solutions Bangalore

9.01

- Performed ETL operations using Azure Data Factory and Databricks.
- worked for Price List Generation Automated Project.
- Developed Data models using OlikView.
- Worked in designing UI for Bundling Simulation using Python and Django.

LANGUAGES

Telugu English

Native or Bilingual Proficiency Full Professional Proficiency

Tamil Hindi

Limited Working Proficiency Limited Working Proficiency

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Technology Madanapalle

07/2016 - 09/2020

Courses

 Electronics and Communication Engineering

INTERESTS

Web Surfing Learning new technologies Coding

Cooking

Listening Music

Python

SKILLS

Azure Data Factory

Natural Language Processing

Machine Learning

Power BI

Microsoft Excel

Flask

Data visualization

PySpark

Statistical Analysis

Apache Kafka

CERTIFICATES

Masters in Data Science from Top Mentor (06/2021 - 10/2021)